citizenm.com 2019-11-15

# 

## _citizenM_  privacy statement

At citizenM, we take your privacy seriously. This Privacy Statement explains how we treat your personal data when you stay with citizenM, visit our websites or purchase our services and products.

### When and why do we use your personal data?

Legal base: explanatory note

| 

This icon means that we need your personal data to enter into a   
 **contract**  with you or to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract.  
  
---|---  
| 

This icon means that we need your personal data to comply with a **legal obligation** to which we are subject.  
  
| 

This icon means that we need your personal data for the purposes of a  **legitimate interest**  pursued by us or by a third party.  
  
| 

This icon means that we process your personal data based on your   
 **consent.**  
  
*Please note that if we need specific personal data in order to comply with a legal obligation or enter into/perform an agreement with you, your refusal to provide such data may result in the inability for you to make a reservation or use the relevant service.  
  
  * #### Reservation

When you make a reservation, you provide us with reservation data such as your name, (email) address, phone number, reservation details and payment information as applicable. We use this data to process the reservation and your stay, for billing purposes, and to communicate with you about your reservation. If you use a social media account to make your reservation, we can retrieve part of the reservation data from your social media account. If you book via a booking agent, the agent will provide us with such data. 

  * #### Account

To simplify future bookings, you can choose to create an account to save the data you provide us during your booking. 

  * #### Administration and retention

Reservation data is stored in our systems for administrative purposes and to comply with data retention obligations. 

  * #### At check-in

In some countries, we are obligated to register specific information when you arrive at a citizenM Hotel. This may include your date of birth, nationality, visa information, place of residence, date of arrival and your profession. We may also be obligated to verify your identity at arrival based on a passport or other ID document. We will only make a copy of your identification document if we are obligated to do so. 

  * #### Room systems

We store data about your use of the systems in the hotel room to ensure that the systems and appliances in our rooms work correctly, such as data regarding the light, entertainment and air-condition systems. This information is used by our 24/7 support team for technical support purposes. We also use such information at an aggregated level to learn about how customers use our services and how we can improve our services. 

  * #### Parking

If you park in our parking garage, we may need to process your license plate number in order to give you access to the parking garage. 

  * #### Security/CCTV

We endeavour to protect our properties, employees, guests and their belongings from illegal activities such as theft and vandalism. Personal data may be processed in this context by or on behalf of citizenM, including the use of CCTV surveillance. 

  * #### Chatbot

Our websites and social media accounts include a chatbot you can talk to about citizenM related matters. Please note that your conversations with the chatbot are stored for self-learning purposes of our chatbot. In addition to answering your queries, we may also use such conversations to learn more about you to improve your experience as our customer. If you use the chatbot, your IP address is collected for technical purposes. 

  * #### Direct marketing

We provide our customers with targeted commercial communications for our own products and services. This means that we base such communications on data we have collected in the context of previous orders/bookings, such as your purchase history, your age, online behaviour on our websites or data we have collected in the context of your stay in our hotel(s).

You can easily opt-out for such communications when you make a reservation via our websites or via the unsubscribe button included in such communications.

With your explicit consent, we and our partners use cookies and similar techniques for the purposes of online cross-site targeted advertising. Please read the "Cookies" section below to find out more. 

  * #### Newsletters

We regularly provide you with newsletters via e-mail if you sign up for such updates. We also send newsletters to existing customers. If you no longer wish to receive such newsletters, you can unsubscribe at any time. 

  * #### Disclosure

In general, we may also process your personal data if necessary to comply with legal obligations, respond to third party claims or requests from public authorities, such as (i) the mandatory storage/containment of certain information because of a criminal investigation, (ii) requests from third parties for access to information (iii) any further instructions from third parties, such as supervisory authorities, that involve data processing. 

  * #### collectionM

If you purchase a product from our collectionM assortment, we use personal data necessary to process your order and to engage in direct marketing activities (see above). Where necessary, we shall base such direct marketing on your consent. 

### Your rights

EU data protection laws may provide you with the following rights:

  * #### Access

You may ask us about the personal data we have about you, and may request us to provide a copy of such data. 

  * #### Erasure, rectification and restriction

If you believe that our processing of your personal data is incorrect, inaccurate, unlawful, excessive, incomplete, no longer relevant, or if you think that your data is stored longer than necessary, you may ask us to change or remove such personal data or restrict such processing activity. 

  * #### Data portability

In some cases, you may receive your personal data provided by yourself in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. 

  * #### Right to object

Where we process your personal data based on a "legitimate interest", you may have the legal right to object to the processing of your personal data. 

  * #### Revoke consent

Where we process personal data based on your consent, you have the right to revoke such consent at any given time. 

  * #### Post mortem right to privacy

You have the right to set instructions regarding the storage, deletion or communication of your personal data after your death. 

  * #### Right to complaint

You have the legal right to lodge a complaint with the competent authority. 

We will review your request or query considering our obligations under applicable mandatory data protection law. We always aim to provide you with a response within 30 days.

### Security, data retention and international transfers

We have implemented appropriate measures to protect your personal data against loss, alteration or any form of unlawful use. Where appropriate, your personal data will be encrypted and securely stored. Access to your personal data by our staff is restricted on a need-to-know basis.

We do not retain personal data longer than is necessary to fulfil the processing purposes as set out in this Privacy Statement (see "When and why do we use your personal data?"). To determine the exact retention period, we take into account applicable minimum data retention obligations, guidance issued by data protection authorities and statute of limitations under applicable law(s).

As we operate internationally, your personal data may be transferred to a citizenM hotel or other recipients (such as franchisees) in a country outside of the country where it was originally collected or outside of your country of residence or nationality. For technical and organizational reasons and in the context of our digital cloud infrastructure, personal data is also transferred to servers located in the US, or to servers located in countries outside of the European Economic Area. In this regard, we have entered into so-called [EU model clauses](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en) with receiving parties or make use of [Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome)  certified partners to ensure compliance with our data protection obligations, or have ensured that a receiving party has in place so-called "binding corporate rules". Please contact us if you wish to receive more information on the specific safeguards we have implemented to ensure an adequate level of data protection regarding such transfers.

### Cookies and similar techniques

This section explains which cookies and similar techniques (hereafter simply referred to as "cookies") we use on our websites (see Annex I for a full list of our domains).

 **Website functionality and optimization**  
citizenM uses cookies that are necessary to provide the requested service. For instance, technical cookies allow you to proceed through different pages of a website with a single login and they remember selections in shopping carts and (order) forms that are filled out on our websites. We also use cookies to measure your behaviour on our websites to learn about the online experience of our website visitors and to improve our websites. In doing so, we also collect the technical features of your terminal equipment and software used by you, such as the type of operating system, the browser settings, the installed plug-ins, the time zone and the screen size of your device. 

 **Cross-site tracking**  
With your consent, third parties (see Annex II below) can store tracking cookies on your device if you visit our website. Such cookies enable these third parties to track your online browsing behaviour across different websites (including the citizenM websites). A common purpose of such tracking cookies is to provide you with targeted advertisements across the websites you visit. We do not control or influence the use by third parties of the information collected through these third party cookies. Please read the privacy policies of these third parties (see Annex II below) to find out more about how they use cookies and process your personal data. 

 **Social media**  
With your consent, our websites use cookies to interact with social media platforms, such as Facebook, Twitter, Foursquare, YouTube and Google+ (see Annex II below for all third party cookies). These cookies are also used to optimize your experience of the social media websites. Please be aware that these cookies may also allow social media platforms to track your online behaviour for cross-site tracking purposes.

 **Withdrawal of your consent**  
You can withdraw your consent at any time by setting your browser to disable cookies and/or to remove all cookies from your browser.

### About us

Your personal data is processed by or on behalf of:  
\- citizenM Operations Holding B.V. (hereinafter referred to as: citizenM Operations), a limited liability company registered under the laws of the Netherlands, having its statutory seat in Amsterdam, the Netherlands and its offices at Leidseweg 219 (2253 AE) Voorschoten, the Netherlands. citizenM Operations Holding B.V. is registered with the Dutch Chamber of Commerce under registration number 34218994;  
and  
\- in the context of your stay or booking regarding one of our hotels, the entities operating the relevant citizenM branded hotel, whether owned or licensed by citizenM Operations B.V. and its wholly and partially owned affiliates (each hereinafter referred to as a: citizenM Hotel; see the full list of our citizenM hotels, and the legal entities that operate these hotels here.

In the context of our hotel services and related services/products, citizenM Operations is the point of contact for all your questions regarding the processing of your personal data.

### Contact us

In case you have any questions in relation to this Privacy Statement or the processing of your personal, please send an email to [privacy@citizenm.com](mailto:privacy@citizenm.com).

Our Data Protection Officer can be contacted via: [dpo@citizenm.com](mailto:dpo@citizenm.com).

This Privacy Statement may change from time to time. Where appropriate, we will notify you of such changes.

Last update: October 18, 2018

### Annex I: citizenM domains

citizenm.com, nl.citizenm.com, fr.citizenm.com, zh.citizenm.com, e.citizenm.com, citizenm.guide, societym.com, citizenmag.com

### Annex II: third parties placing cookies on our websites

AdRoll - [privacy policy](https://www.adroll.com/about/privacy)  
AdRoll Pixel - [privacy policy](https://www.adroll.com/about/privacy)  
AdRoll Roundtrip - [privacy policy](https://www.adroll.com/about/privacy)  
AOL Advertising - [privacy policy](https://policies.oath.com/xw/en/oath/privacy/intl/index.html)  
AppNexus - [privacy policy](https://www.appnexus.com/en/company/platform-privacy-policy)  
BidSwitch (IPONWEB) - [privacy policy](http://www.iponweb.com/privacy-policy/)  
Bing Ads (Microsoft Advertising) - [privacy policy](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement/)  
DoubleClick - [privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
DoubleClick Floodlight (Google) - [privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Facebook Connect - [privacy policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/)  
Facebook Custom Audience - [privacy policy](https://www.facebook.com/full_data_use_policy)  
Facebook Pixel - [privacy policy](https://www.facebook.com/full_data_use_policy)  
Facebook Social Plugins - [privacy policy](https://www.facebook.com/full_data_use_policy)  
Flashtalking - [privacy policy](http://www.flashtalking.com/privacypolicy/)  
GA audiences - [privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Google Adwords User List - [privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Google Analytics - [privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Google Dynamic Remarketing - [privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Google Tag Manager - [privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Google Tag Manager Web Tracking - [privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Google+ Platform - [privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy)  
Hotjar - [privacy policy](http://www.hotjar.com/privacy)  
Index Exchange (Formerly Casale Media) - [privacy policy](https://www.indexexchange.com/)  
Intercom - [privacy policy](https://docs.intercom.com/pricing-privacy-and-terms/intercom-inc-privacy-policy)  
LinkedIn ads - [privacy policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy)  
LinkedIn Marketing Solutions - [privacy policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy)  
LiveRamp - [privacy policy](https://liveramp.com/privacy/)  
MyFonts Counter - [privacy policy](https://www.myfonts.com/info/legal/#Privacy)  
OpenX - [privacy policy](https://www.openx.com/legal/privacy-policy/)  
PubMatic - [privacy policy](http://www.pubmatic.com/privacy-policy.php)  
Rocket Fuel - [privacy policy](http://rocketfuel.com/privacy/)  
Rubicon - [privacy policy](https://rubiconproject.com/rubicon-project-yield-optimization-privacy-policy/)  
Taboola - [privacy policy](https://www.taboola.com/privacy-policy)  
TripleLift - [privacy policy  
](https://triplelift.com/privacy/)Twitter Advertising - [privacy policy](https://twitter.com/privacy?lang=en)[  
](https://triplelift.com/privacy/)WisePops - [privacy policy  
](https://wisepops.com/terms/)Yahoo Ad Exchange - [privacy policy  
](https://policies.yahoo.com/us/en/yahoo/privacy/index.htm)Yieldr - [privacy policy](https://www.yieldr.com/privacy/)

Last updated: May 31 2019
